

DevOps Engineer seeking roles in Software Engineering, Software

Development, Application Support, Project Management, Change Management, System

Administration, Troubleshooting, Android

Development, Installation, Jenkins, Docker, Python, MySQL, JIRA, AWS, Git



Current Designation: DevOps Engineer Total Experience: 6 Year(s) 0 Month(s)

Current Company: Prueba India Software Pvt. Ltd Notice Period: 3 Months

Current Location: MANIPAL Highest Degree: BCA [Computers]

Pref. Location: Bengaluru / Bangalore, Chennai, Mysore Functional Area: IT Software - Application Programming /

Maintenance

Role: Software Developer

Industry: IT-Software/Software Services

Marital Status: Single/unmarried

Key Skills: DevOps Engineer,Software Developer,Software Engineering,Software Development,Application Support,Project Management,Change Management,System Administration,Troubleshooting,Android

Development, Installation, Jenkins, Docker, Python, MySQL, JIRA, AWS, Git

Verified: Phone Number | Email - id

Last Active: 21-Jan-21 Last Modified: 21-Jan-21

### Summary

As an experienced DevOps Engineer, dedicated to optimisation and understanding of melding of operations and development, to quickly deliver code to customers.

A company where my acquired knowledge and professional and technical skills should be utilized to its fullest and where I can grow professionally.

Strong analytical skills combined with experience in object oriented programming techniques.

Compatible team player with good project and people management skills.

# Work Experience

#### Prueba India Software Pvt. Ltd as DevOps Engineer

Dec 2016 to Till Date

Good knowledge of Installation, administration & troubleshooting skills on various flavors of Linux. Create and maintain fully automated CI/CD pipelines for code deployment using terraform.

Actively manage, improve, and monitor cloud infrastructure on AWS, EC2,S3,VPC,Lambda and RDS, including backups, patches, and scaling

Built and deployed Docker containers to break up monolithic app into microservices, improving developer workflow, increasing scalability, and optimizing speed.

Have used Postgresql DBMS inside the AWS instances also within the Docker containers.

Automated build and deployment using CircleCI and Jenkins

Installed and configured monitoring tool Outlyer, prometheus and grafana to constantly monitor network bandwidth, memory usage, and hard drive status, status of the services running within AWS instances, docker and kubernetes services etc.

Utilized Kubernetes for the runtime environment of the CI/CD system to build, test deploy.

Also worked in Xamarin and Android development for the initial one year.

A1Logics as Software Engineer

Sep 2015 to Nov 2016

Developed Windows applications using c#.net and Microsoft SQL server Developed Web applications using asp.net and Microsoft SQL server Had given project guidance to interns

**TAPMI** as System Administrator Oct 2014 to Aug 2015

worked as a system administrator

### **Education**

UG: BCA (Computers) from mahatma gandhi memorial college in 2014

#### **IT Skills**

Skill Name	Version Last Used Experience
Ubuntu ,Windows, Linux,, Mac OS	
PostgreSql, MySql, RDS Aurora	
Docker, Kubernetes, Amazon AWS	
Shell Script , Python, Yaml, Git, GitHuB	
Jira,Pivotal tracker, Saltstack, Helm	
CircleCI, Jenkins, Terraform	
MS Office, Vi editor, VS Code	

## Languages Known

Language	Proficiency	Read	Write	Speak
English	Proficient			
Hindi	Proficient			
Kannada	Expert			
Tulu	Expert			

#### **Affirmative Action**

Category: OBC - non-creamy Physically Challenged: No

#### **Work Authorization**

Job Type: Permanent / Temporary

Employment Status: Full Time, Part Time